Guide to the Victor Lloyd Butterfield Papers, 1910 - 1975
Victor Lloyd Butterfield Papers 1910 - 1975
- Butterfield Papers1910-1975
  - Connecticut Higher Education Facilities Finance Agency (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - Faculty -- Department Memoranda -- Administration - Admissions (Box 55, Folder 7)
  - Faculty -- Department Memoranda -- Art (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - Faculty -- Department Memoranda -- Astronomy (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - Faculty -- Department Memoranda -- Biology (Box 56, Folder 3)
  - Faculty -- Department Memoranda -- Chemistry (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - Faculty -- Department Memoranda -- Classics (Box 56, Folder 5)
  - Faculty -- Department Memoranda -- Economics (Box 56, Folder 6)
  - Faculty -- Department Memoranda -- English (Box 56, Folder 7)
  - Faculty -- Department Memoranda -- Geology (Box 56, Folder 8)
  - Faculty -- Department Memoranda -- German (Box 56, Folder 9)
  - Faculty -- Department Memoranda -- Government (Box 56, Folder 10)
  - Faculty -- Department Memoranda -- History (Box 56, Folder 11)
  - Faculty -- Department Memoranda -- Humanities (Box 56, Folder 12)
  - Faculty -- Department Memoranda -- Mathematics (Box 56, Folder 13)
  - Faculty -- Department Memoranda -- Music (Box 56, Folder 14)
  - Faculty -- Department Memoranda -- Philosophy (Box 56, Folder 15)
  - Faculty -- Department Memoranda -- Physics (Box 56, Folder 16)
  - Faculty -- Department Memoranda -- Physical Education (Box 56, Folder 17)
  - Faculty -- Department Memoranda -- Religion (Box 56, Folder 18)
  - Faculty -- Department Memoranda -- Romance Languages (Box 56, Folder 19)
  - Faculty -- Department Memoranda -- Russian (Box 56, Folder 20)
  - Faculty -- Department Memoranda -- Psychology (Box 56, Folder 21)
  - Faculty -- Department Memoranda -- Theater (Box 56, Folder 22)
  - Faculty -- Department Memoranda -- Vocational (Box 56, Folder 23)
  - Graduate Division -- Scholarly Press (Box 56, Folder 24)
  - National Science Foundation (Box 56, Folder 25)
  - Graduate Division -- School Services and Publications (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - Graduate Summer School (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - Honorary Degrees (Box 57, Folder 3)
  - I.J.K.L.M.N. (Box 57, Folder 4)
  - Library (Box 57, Folder 5)
  - Presdient's Staff (Box 57, Folder 6)
  - Trustees -- Buildings and Grounds (Box 57, Folder 7)
  - Trustees -- Education Committee (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - Trustees -- Meetings (Box 58, Folder 2)
  - White House Conference (Box 58, Folder 3)
  - Wilbraham Academy (Box 58, Folder 4)
  - UVWXYZ (Box 58, Folder 5)
  - Wesleyan Center for Advanced Studies (Box 58, Folder 6)
  - Wesleyan Center -- Individuals (Box 58, Folder 7)
  - Wesleyan Center for Advanced Studies and the American Council of Learned Societies (Box 59, Folder 1)
  - Wesleyan in Perspective (Box 59, Folder 2)
  - A.B.C. (Box 59, Folder 3)
  - Airlines (Box 59, Folder 4)
  - Associations -- General (Box 59, Folder 5-6)
  - Associations of American Colleges -- Com. of Graduate and Professional Study (Box 59, Folder 7)
  - Association of American Colleges -- Com. on College and Society (Box 59, Folder 8)
  - Business -- Budget (Box 60, Folder 1)
  - Calendar (Box 60, Folder 2)
  - Colleges (Box 60, Folder 3)
  - Committee of 100 -- Alumni Complaints (Box 60, Folder 4)
  - Curriculum Committee (Box 60, Folder 5)
  - Curriculum Section: American Studies (Box 60, Folder 6)
  - Curriculum Section: Center for Religious Dialogue (Box 60, Folder 7)
  - Curriculum Section: College of Contrasting Cultures (Box 60, Folder 8)
  - Curriculum Section: College of Latin American Studies (Box 60, Folder 9)
  - Curriculum Section: Oriental Language (Box 60, Folder 10)
  - Curriculum Section: Life Sciences (Box 60, Folder 11)
  - Curriculum Section: New University (Box 60, Folder 12)
  - Curriculum Section: Public Affairs (Box 60, Folder 13)
  - Curriculum Section: Cosmic Physics (Box 60, Folder 14)
  - Curriculum Section: Credit Without Grade (Box 60, Folder 15)
  - Curriculum Section: Humanistic Studies (Box 60, Folder 16)
  - Curriculum Section: Humanities 1-2 (Box 60, Folder 17)
  - Curriculum Section: Humanities 51-52 (Box 60, Folder 18)
  - Curriculum Section: Language (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - Curriculum Section: Russian (Box 61, Folder 2)
  - Curriculum Section: Science 1-2 (Box 61, Folder 3)
  - Curriculum Section: Science 3-4 (Box 61, Folder 4)
  - Curriculum Section: Science Advisory Committee (Box 61, Folder 5)
  - Development (Box 61, Folder 6)
  - D.E.F.G.H. (Box 61, Folder 7)
  - George F. Baker Trust (Box 61, Folder 8)
  - Reed Baldwin Fellowship (Box 61, Folder 9)
  - John Blanchard Clark Fellowships (Box 61, Folder 10)
  - Fulbright Scholarships (Box 61, Folder 11)
  - Squire Fellowship (Box 61, Folder 12)
  - Wesleyan Industrial Scientific Research (Box 61, Folder 13)
  - Winchester Fellowship (Box 61, Folder 14)
  - Woodrow Wilson Fellowships (Box 61, Folder 15)
  - Food Service (Box 61, Folder 16)
  - Graduate Division -- Summer School (Box 61, Folder 17)
  - Grants -- Industrial A-G (Box 61, Folder 18)
  - Grants -- Industrial H-Z (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - Honorary Degrees (Box 62, Folder 2)
  - Inquiries (Box 62, Folder 3)
  - Itinerary (Box 62, Folder 4)
  - I.J.K.L.M.N. (Box 62, Folder 5)
  - O.P.Q.R.S.T. (Box 62, Folder 6)
  - U.V.W.X.Y.Z. (Box 62, Folder 7)
  - Recommendations (Box 62, Folder 8)
  - Television (Box 62, Folder 9)
  - Trustees -- Agenda (Box 62, Folder 10)
  - Trustees -- Biographical Material (Box 63, Folder 1)
  - Trustees -- By-laws (Box 63, Folder 2)
  - Trustees -- B&G (Box 63, Folder 3)
  - Trustees -- Budget (Box 63, Folder 4)
  - Trustees -- Education (Box 63, Folder 5)
  - Trustees -- Finance (Box 63, Folder 6)
  - Trustees -- Fraternities Committee (Box 63, Folder 7)
  - Trustees -- Long-range Planning (Box 63, Folder 8)
  - Trustees -- Special Meeting (Box 63, Folder 9)
  - Trustee Meeting (Box 63, Folder 10)
  - Trustee Meeting (Box 63, Folder 11)
  - Trustee Meeting (Box 63, Folder 12)
  - Trustee Meeting (Box 63, Folder 13)
  - Trustee Meeting (Box 63, Folder 14)
  - Trustees -- Nominations (Box 63, Folder 15)
  - Wesleyan Center (General Correspondence) (Box 63, Folder 16)
  - Wesleyan in Perspective (Box 63, Folder 17)
  - Administration (Box 64, Folder 1)
    Processing note 1988 May 31: Curriculum vitae of candidates and correspondence, transcripts; some folders without dates are empty.
  - Anthropology (Box 64, Folder 2)
  - Art (Box 64, Folder 3)
  - Asian Studies (Box 64, Folder 4)
  - Astronomy (Box 64, Folder 5)
  - Biology (Box 64, Folder 6)
  - The Center for Advanced Studies (Box 64, Folder 7)
  - Chemistry (Box 64, Folder 8)
  - Classics (Box 64, Folder 9)
  - Development (Box 64, Folder 10)
  - Director, College of Letters (Box 64, Folder 11)
  - Dramatics (Box 64, Folder 12)
  - Economics (Box 64, Folder 13)
  - Education (Box 64, Folder 14)
  - English (Box 64, Folder 15)
  - Geology (Box 64, Folder 16)
  - Geography (Box 64, Folder 17)
  - German (Box 64, Folder 18)
  - Government (Box 64, Folder 19)
  - Public Affairs (Box 64, Folder 20)
  - Headmaster (Box 64, Folder 21)
  - History (Box 64, Folder 22)
  - Humanities (Box 64, Folder 23)
  - Librarian (Box 64, Folder 24)
  - Mathematics (Box 64, Folder 25)
  - Master of Arts in Teaching (Box 64, Folder 26)
  - Miscellany (Box 64, Folder 27)
  - Music (Box 64, Folder 28)
  - Physics (Box 64, Folder 29)
  - Philosophy of Science (Box 64, Folder 30)
  - Philosophy (Box 65, Folder 1)
  - Physical Education (Box 65, Folder 2)
  - Physical Science (Box 65, Folder 3)
  - Psychology (Box 65, Folder 4)
  - Provost (Box 65, Folder 5)
  - Public Relations (Box 65, Folder 6)
  - Public Speaking (Box 65, Folder 7)
  - Religion (Box 65, Folder 8)
  - Remedial Reading (Box 65, Folder 9)
  - Romance Languages (Box 65, Folder 10)
  - Sociology, current (Box 65, Folder 11)
  - Russian (Box 65, Folder 12)
  - Summer School Director (Box 65, Folder 13)
  - Theater (Box 65, Folder 14)
  - Administration (Box 65, Folder 15)
  - Anthropology (Box 65, Folder 16)
  - Art (Box 65, Folder 17)
  - Asian Studies (Box 65, Folder 18)
  - Astronomy (Box 66, Folder 1)
  - Biology (Box 66, Folder 2)
  - Chemistry (Box 66, Folder 3)
  - Classics (Box 66, Folder 4)
  - Dean of Men (Box 66, Folder 5)
  - Dean of Science and Physics Names A-P (Box 66, Folder 6-8)
  - Dean of Science and Physics Names R-Z (Box 66, Folder 9-10)
  - Dean of Sciences (Correspondence) (Box 67, Folder 1)
  - Dramatics (Box 67, Folder 2)
  - Economics (Box 67, Folder 3)
  - English (Box 67, Folder 4)
  - Geology (Box 67, Folder 5)
  - Government (Box 67, Folder 6)
  - History (Box 67, Folder 7)
  - Mathematics (Box 67, Folder 8-9)
  - Master of Arts in Teaching Program (Box 67, Folder 10)
  - Miscellany (Box 67, Folder 11)
  - Philosophy (Box 67, Folder 12)
  - Philosophy of Science (Box 67, Folder 13)
  - Psychology (Box 67, Folder 14)
  - Public Speaking (Box 67, Folder 15)
  - Russian (Box 67, Folder 16)
  - Romance Languages (Box 67, Folder 17)
  - Empty file organizer labeled "Dr. Victor L Butterfield (Box 67, Folder 18)
  - Stuart Hedden (Box 67, Folder 19)
  - Conference on Moral and Ethical Values, Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies (Box 68, Folder 1)
  - The College Plan (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - Cornell University (Box 68, Folder 3)
  - Cornell University (Box 68, Folder 4)
  - Connecticut State Department of Education (Box 68, Folder 5)
  - Administrative Staff Meetings (Box 68, Folder 6)
  - Educational Policy Committee (Box 68, Folder 7)
  - Women's Education (Box 68, Folder 8)
  - Ecucational Policy Committee (Box 68, Folder 9)
  - Faculty Staffing and Projections (Box 68, Folder 10)
  - College Plans (Box 68, Folder 11)
  - Cornell University (Box 69, Folder 1)
  - Connecticut Study of Role fo Public Schools (Box 69, Folder 2)
  - Personal Letters of Appreciation (Box 69, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence (Box 69, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence (Box 69, Folder 5)
  - VLB Resignation and Announcement (Box 69, Folder 6)
  - VLB Retirement Arrangements (Box 69, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence (Box 69, Folder 8)
  - VLB Biographical (Box 69, Folder 9)
  - VLB Office Budget (Box 69, Folder 10)
  - University of California at Santa Cruz (Box 69, Folder 11)
  - Special Committee on Liberal Studies (Box 69, Folder 12)
  - Society for Religion in Higher Education (Box 69, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence (Box 69, Folder 14)
  - VLB re COL (letter to Professors Schwaber and Hallie) (Box 70, Folder 1)
  - VLB to David re Role of College President (Box 70, Folder 2)
  - VLB Listing in Directory of American Scholars (Box 70, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence (Box 70, Folder 4)
  - Society for Values in Higher Education (VLB's role) (Box 70, Folder 5)
  - VLB to CGCampbell (Box 70, Folder 6)
  - Parent's Day at Wesleyan (Box 70, Folder 7)
  - The Wesleyan Story: The Importance of Moral Capital (from Carnegie Commission study entitled "Academic Transformation.. " (Box 70, Folder 8)
  - A Historical Overview (Box 70, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence with Mario de la Torre re Latin American prints (Box 70, Folder 10)
  - Letters of Appreciation (Box 70, Folder 11)
  - Scrutiny, Amherst College (Box 70, Folder 12)
  - Looking the Gift Horse in the Mouth, J.H. Knowles, President, The Rockefeller Foundation (Box 70, Folder 13)
  - B.C. Hallowell List of Priorities (Box 70, Folder 14)
  - N. Rudich to VLB re College Plan in Perspective (Box 70, Folder 15)
  - Deerfield Academy (Box 70, Folder 16)
  - Deerfield Academy, Report on Study of Coeducation (Box 70, Folder 17)
  - Draft of Letter to C.G. Campbell re Hedden's History of Wesleyan Press (Box 70, Folder 18)
    missing
  - The Wesleyan University Press: An Esoteric History by Stuart Hedden (Box 70, Folder 19)
  - Academy for Educational Development (Box 70, Folder 20)
  - Alternatives for Wesleyan 1975-1980 (three volumes, green, orange and purple, 1975) (Box 70, Folder 21)
  - FPC Report: A Plan for Financial Stability (Box 71, Folder 1)
  - Wesleyan University Press History (notes) (Box 71, Folder 2)
  - Listings of Board of Trustees (Box 71, Folder 3)
  - Finance Committee Report by Stuart Hedden (Box 71, Folder 4)
  - Press Release on death of Michael Rapuano (Box 71, Folder 5)
  - Skidmore College re J.C. Palamountain (Box 71, Folder 6)
  - New College, Inc., Meeting of Executive Committee, etc. (Box 71, Folder 7)
  - Nathan Pusey to American Council on Education re China (Box 71, Folder 8)
  - Conference on Ethics of Teaching and Research (Box 71, Folder 9)
  - John D. Maguire, President, State University of New York at Westbury (Box 71, Folder 10)
  - Edwin C. Johnson, Jr. '41 (Box 71, Folder 11)
  - Hayden V. White, Director, Center for Humanities re Growth and Innovation in the Humanities at Wesleyan (Box 71, Folder 12)
  - Observations on Problems and Methods of the Small Liberal College by VLB (Report to Carnegie Corporation in partial fulfillment of obligations incurred from their 1939-1940 Grant-in-Aid) (Box 71, Folder 13)
  - Comparative Guide to American Colleges (Box 71, Folder 14)
  - Oxford University, VLB's Interviews and People Suggested (Box 71, Folder 15)
  - Cambridge University, VLB's interviews and People Suggested (Box 71, Folder 16)
  - England, Scotland, Ireland & the Continent, VLB's Interviews and People Suggested (Box 71, Folder 17)
  - Annual Reports of Departments (Box 71, Folder 18)
  - Ford Foundation (VLB Consultant) (Box 71, Folder 19)
  - New College, incl correspondence re Search for President (Box 72, Folder 1)
  - Candidates for Presidency of New College (Box 72, Folder 2)
  - Deerfield Academy, general correspondence (Box 72, Folder 3)
  - Deefield Academy, evaluation (Box 72, Folder 4)
  - Study of Liberal Arts Colleges, Ford Foundation (Box 72, Folder 5)
  - Trustees of Deerfield Academy, Special Meeting (Box 72, Folder 6)
  - Trustees of Deerfield Academy, Annual Meeting (Box 72, Folder 7)
  - Danforth Foundation -- Harbison Award for Distinguished Teaching (Box 73, Folder 1)
  - Harbison Board of Selection (Box 73, Folder 2)
  - VLB as Chair of Harbison Awards (Box 73, Folder 3)
  - Danforth Foundation re establishment of a national commission on higher education (Box 73, Folder 4)
  - Danforth Foundation (Box 73, Folder 5)
  - Staff Analysis, Long-range Planning and Development (Box 73, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence incl. Boston College Activity (Box 74, Folder 1)
  - Aspen Institute (Box 74, Folder 2)
  - VLB to T.C. Dunham, re co-ordinate college for women (Box 74, Folder 3)
  - E.J. Simmons, Acting Director, Center for Advanced Studies, to VLB (Box 74, Folder 4)
  - Report of University Archivist (Box 74, Folder 5)
  - H.B. Matthews to VLB re Wesleyan Press (incl. correspondence from Stuart Hedden) (Box 74, Folder 6)
  - Michael A. Pawel, '67 to VLB re N. Rudich (Box 74, Folder 7)
  - Headmaster's Report (Box 74, Folder 8)
  - Charles A. Wright to VLB (Box 74, Folder 9)
  - George ?, University of Notre Dame to VLB (Box 74, Folder 10)
  - Program for Educational Leadership (Box 74, Folder 11)
  - J. Kiermaier, Long Island University to VLB (Box 74, Folder 12)
  - John C. Hoy, University of California, Irvine to VLB (Box 74, Folder 13)
  - Ida Wallace, Director, Washington Office, Associatied Colleges of Midwest, to VLB (Box 74, Folder 14)
  - News Clipping about Blind Drive (Box 74, Folder 15)
  - Donald Bush, Treasurer, Century Association to VLB (Box 74, Folder 16)
  - Arthur T. Vanderbilt II to VLB (Box 74, Folder 17)
  - Ford Foundation to VLB (Box 74, Folder 18)
  - Middle East (Box 74, Folder 19-21)
    Victor Butterfield's reports on his interviews with those in education in the Middle East give a clear picture of the situation at that time (1952-1953). The details reflect Butterfield's values. While Butterfield was making his study, the Fund for Advancement of Education, a division of the Ford Foundation, under whose auspices he made the study, was reorganized and its field limited to the United States. Butterfield's study was then transferred to the Overseas [Activities] Division of the Ford Foundation, which was concentrating on projects to help the countries economically. They had no interest in Education - rather in agriculture and engineering. Leadership in the Ford Foundation also changed. Butterfield later mentioned his report to the new head who knew nothing of it. Nothing was ever done.
  - Near East (Box 74, Folder 22)
  - Near East - Fund for the Advancement of Education 1st Near East Trip (Box 74, Folder 23)
  - Near East - Fund for the Advancement of Education 2nd Near East Trip (Box 74, Folder 24-25)
  - General (Box 74, Folder 26)
    Period during which Victor Butterfield served as Acting President
  - VLB and Football (from Paton) (Box 75, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous (from Paton) (Box 75, Folder 2)
  - New College (Box 75, Folder 3-10)
  - General Correspondence A-Z (Box 76, Folder 1-18)
  - Major Activites (Box 76, Folder 19)
  - Graduate Education: A Study of the Assessment of Quality (report of the Commission on Plans & Objectives for Higher Education - VLB member) (Box 76, Folder 20)
    1 binder
  - Carnegie Corporation (Box 76, Folder 21)
  - Tidewater Oils (Box 76, Folder 22)
  - Aspen Institute on 1965 Humanistic Studies (Box 76, Folder 23)
  - American Council on Education (Box 77, Folder 1)
  - Braitmeyer Foundation (Box 77, Folder 2-3)
  - Cannel Meetings (Box 77, Folder 4)
  - The Center for American Living, Inc. (Box 77, Folder 5)
  - Cornell University (Box 77, Folder 6)
  - Danforth Foundation (Box 77, Folder 7)
  - Harbison-Danforth Foundation (Box 77, Folder 8)
  - Post retirement (Box 77, Folder 9)
  - Cornell (Box 77, Folder 10)
  - Academy for Educational Development, Davidson College Study (Box 77, Folder 11)
  - Academy for Educational Development, Davidson College, VLB's study, report (Box 78, Folder 1)
  - Future of Davidson College -- report (Box 78, Folder 2)
  - Deerfield Academy (Box 78, Folder 3)
  - Ford Foundation Study of Undergraduate Education (Box 78, Folder 4)
  - Alex Knopp -- Assistant on Ford Study (Box 78, Folder 5)
  - Fund for Advancement of Education (Box 78, Folder 6)
  - VLB Report to FAE on Education in Arab Countries [confidential] (Box 78, Folder 7)
  - Ford Foundation (Box 78, Folder 8)
  - FAE Expenses (Box 78, Folder 9)
  - FAE Faculty Fellowship Committee (Box 79, Folder 1-2)
  - Harvard -- Committee to visit Philosophy Dept. (Box 79, Folder 3)
  - Harvard Divinity Committee (Box 79, Folder 4)
  - Hazen Foundation (Box 79, Folder 5-6)
  - Colleges - Harvard Divinity School Committee, visitor (Box 79, Folder 7)
  - Independent University (England) (Box 79, Folder 8)
  - Rockefeller Arts and Humanities (Box 80, Folder 1)
  - Society for Religion in Higher Education (Box 80, Folder 2-3)
    Empty, note states VLB's records are on file at the Society Office in New Haven, Divinity School Building
  - Cluster College Concept (Box 80, Folder 4)
  - Financial Aspects ? Cluster & Non-Cluster College (Box 80, Folder 5)
  - Vassar -- Nell Ehrich (Box 80, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 80, Folder 7)
  - Wilbraham Academy (Box 80, Folder 8)
  - VLB Office Budget (Box 80, Folder 9)
  - Act #9910 (VLB) (Box 80, Folder 10)
  - 9911 Expense Summaries -- VLB (Box 80, Folder 11)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Executive Committee Memoranda (Box 80, Folder 12)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, AAC Meeting, Washington (Box 80, Folder 13)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, AAC Meeting, Washington (Box 80, Folder 14)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Executive Committee Meeting, Barnard College (Box 80, Folder 15)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Execuitve Committee Meeting (Box 80, Folder 16)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Executive Committee Meeting, Barnard College (Box 80, Folder 17)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Executive Committee Meeting, The Deanery - Barnard College (Box 80, Folder 18)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Executive Committee Meeting, NY (Box 80, Folder 19)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Executive Meeting, Barnard College, NY (Box 80, Folder 20)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Executive Committee Meeting, The Deanery (Box 81, Folder 1)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Planning Meeting, Wesleyan (Box 81, Folder 2)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies (Box 81, Folder 3)
  - Association of American Colleges, Participants & Suggestions (Box 81, Folder 4)
  - Association of American Colleges, Commission on Liberal Learning (Box 81, Folder 5)
  - Acct # 9911, S.C.L.S. (Box 81, Folder 6)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Regional Meeting, Duke (Box 81, Folder 7)
  - S.P.L.S. - Finances (Box 81, Folder 8)
  - Association of American Colleges (Box 81, Folder 9)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Basic Material for Documents (Box 81, Folder 10)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies (Box 81, Folder 11)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Meeting (Box 81, Folder 12)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Regional Meeting, Vanderbilt (Box 81, Folder 13)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, VLB Chariman (Box 81, Folder 14)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Regional Meeting, Berkeley (Box 82, Folder 1)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Regional Meeting, Berkeley (Box 82, Folder 2)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Regional Meetings, Bloomington, Indiana (Box 82, Folder 3)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Regional Meeting, Notre Dame, Indiana (Box 82, Folder 4)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Conference on Graduate Education, Postponed until Fall 1970 (Box 82, Folder 5)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Seattle Washington, meeting (Box 82, Folder 6)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, (Loyola U.) L.A. meeting (Box 82, Folder 7)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Nebraska Regional Mtg. (Box 82, Folder 8)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Michigan Regional Mtg. (Box 82, Folder 9)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Regional Meeting, Kansas City, MO (Box 82, Folder 10)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Florida Meeting, Messrs. Spivey & Buri (Box 82, Folder 11)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Regional Meeting, Exeter, N.H. (Box 83, Folder 1)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Misc. Correspondence "B" (Box 83, Folder 2)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Misc. Correspondence "C" (Box 83, Folder 3)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Misc. Correspondence "D" (Box 83, Folder 4)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Misc. Correspondence "E" (Box 83, Folder 5)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Misc. Correspondence "F" (Box 83, Folder 6)